# M TABARIK ASIF

ETHICAL HACKER, PENETRATION TESTER, BUG HUNTER, CYBERSECURITY PROFESSIONAL

**)** (+92) 320-8098749

in LinkedIn Profile

mtabarikasif@gmail.com

**mtabarikasif** 

## PROFILE

Experienced Cybersecurity professional, Ethical Hacker and Bug Bounty Hunter with over 4 years of real-world experience, Specializes offensive and defensive security. Proficient in Web/API hacking, automation, Cloud Security, OWASP top 10, Cyber Security tools and Scripting. A Curious Learner, Tech Enthusiast, President Society of Computer Technology.

#### EDUCATION

// Bachelor of CS
Hazara University
- (2024)

SKILLS

// Technical Skills

BASH Scripting Reconnaissance Web/API Hacking OWASP Top 10 Google Dorking CVSS

// Soft Skills

Collaborations Adaptable Creative Thinking Team Work Ethics

// Tools

Burp Suite SQLMap Metasploit Nmap Nessus Nikto WAF

AWARDS

Tecno Hall of Fame

Safe Keeper

**Submission Shogun L3** Bugcrowd - 2023

Private Hall of Fame

Achieved HOF on private bug bounty Programs

Elite Member Township local Welfare - 2023

**SCT Performance Award** 

CS Society Award

#### PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Organized Departmental Activities (Conferences and Project Exhibitions), Conducted Cyber security workshops in CS department to spread awareness and teach ethical hacking techniques based on previously discovered vulnerabilities.

- President Society of Computer Technology (2023-2024)
- IBM Cyber Security Analyst (2024)
- Google Cybersecurity Professional Certificate (2023)
- CompTIA Security+ (Udemy) (2024)
- LinkedIn Learning Become an Ethical Hacker (2022)
- Other Relevant Security Certifications (TCM Sec, Udemy)

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Bug Hunting** *Bugcrowd*, *Hackerone*, *Private* | *Remote* | *2020 - Present* Proficiently identified and resolved critical vulnerabilities across <u>Bugcrowd</u>, HackerOne, and private platforms, demonstrating proficiency in security assessments. Fostered efficient **collaborations** and swift **issue resolution** through professional communication standards.

- Successfully discovered and reported high-impact bugs, encompassing SQLI, XSS, IDOR, Broken Authentication, and Security Misconfigurations.
- Executed an **Authentication Bypass vulnerability (P1)** on Jenkins, leading to the resolution of a critical bug for a globally recognized, multibillion-dollar soft drinks company.
- Uncovered exposed **database backups** and live data on <u>Telefonica</u> <u>Germany's</u> assets and <u>Tecno</u> respectively, highlighting security gaps and contributing to enhanced data protection measures.
- Identified and reported an **RXSS vulnerability** on Tecno, resulting in the attainment of Hall of Fame recognition.

Virtual Internships and Job Simulations Forage | 2023,2024 Successfully Completed Virtual internships and Job simulations, for Mastercard, ANZ Australia, JPMorgan Chase & Co and Clifford Chance. Deepening expertise in business awareness, legal assessment, network traffic analysis, antiphishing tactics, standards compliance impact analysis, and social engineering concepts.

**Projects** Cybersecurity Projects | 2020 - Present Projects developed exclusively for the field of Cybersecurity, spanning from 2020 to the present.

- Final Year Project: Developed a web vulnerability scanner as FYP.
- Python Keylogger: A <u>Python keylogger</u> with screenshot capabilities Emphasized ethical user for educational purposes and testing scenarios.
- **Automation Projects:** <u>Developed diverse automation projects</u>, including **automated recon**, versatile **bash scripts**, efficient in bug bounty.
- AWS WAF Deployment: Designed and implemented AWS WAF, acquiring expertise in ACLs, rules, bot control, integrations, IP sets and rule groups for effective security.
- Semester Projects: Executed multiple <u>semester projects</u> across diverse language and technologies, exploring new skill in NLP-based chatbots, LLMs Hacking, Networking tools and various other projects.